Niall Miner

niallminer.wordpress.com – 832-341-6343 – niallminer@gmail.com

SUMMARY
Website Developer with experience in full stack development, defect tracking, database management, who has releases for

Website Developer with experience in full stack development, defect tracking, database management, who has releases for websites, mobile applications, and video games. Avid programmer with a degree in Computer Science who is always improving both his technical and interpersonal skills as well as implementing creativity into the projects he's involved in.

------ EXPERIENCE

WellFence/Drilling Tools Intl. - Houston, TX

Software Engineer: (Nov 2018 - Present)

Create functionality and design of the company web app that is both user-facing, as well as client -facing using Ruby on Rails. The site keeps track of user information and activity for different well locations for the Permian Basin. Developed a site that has increased automation and ease of use with features like AWS database connections, REST API calls, and Twilio. Generate charts so clients have relevant information and patterns about their employees as well as the ability for clients to view site rosters, event history, and user compliance digitally.

- <u>AJAX Automation</u> optimized code written by a previous engineer by using AJAX and REST API calls. Refactored and automated processes that were cumbersome to users
- <u>UI/UX Design</u> designed UI elements for the site, with feedback from internal and external users of the application, and made the site responsive for mobile users, so clients can use our software anywhere.

Six Foot Games - Houston, TX *QA Tester: (June 2018 - Oct 2018)*

Troubleshooted and reported bugs found for varying versions of the video game Dreadnought using JIRA and Confluence. Implemented pushing/pulling patches and builds to multiple machines to test on different platforms such as PC and PlayStation 4. Responsible for the development, maintenance and execution of high quality specialized testing procedures and support services during the QA process, leveraging expert-level knowledge within my area of specialization.

• <u>Steam Release</u> - helped the company successfully release the video game Dreadnought on Steam, as well as worked tirelessly to verify that the submission was valid and up to Steam's standards so that it could be launched live.

The Trefny Center - Golden, CO

Lead Instructional Media Developer: (Jan 2016 - May 2018)

Renewed the department's website with a whole new design and functionality, while collaborating with faculty to receive feedback on user experience. Improved the quality of teaching that the faculty can provide at Colorado School of Mines by producing supplemental instructional videos and graphics. Collaborated with faculty to help them achieve a higher productivity and further their teaching courses.

Deep Space Systems - Littleton, CO

Software Engineer Intern: (Aug 2016 - Dec 2016)

Constructed and tested hardware kits that will later be used as final products on the Orion Spacecraft and troubleshooted software problems by controlling cameras remotely through a Linux terminal. Used automation in Linux environments that created and ran bash scripts for command line interaction to run tests and collect results.

EDUCATION
EDUCATION
Colorado School of Mines Graduate - May 2018
BS in Computer Science - Cumulative GPA: 3.641
ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Proficient in Ruby on Rails, AJAX, REST APIs, JavaScript, HTML5 & CSS3, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Heroku, GitHub, JIRA, Confluence, Testrail. Game engine experience in Godot, Unreal Engine, Unity